opusdei.org 2018-09-06

# Opus Dei - Privacy policy and cookies - legal notice

## legal notice

The privacy policy of this website is described here to comply with the provisions of the existing regulations covering databases, e-commerce and use of personal information.

 **Declaration** by **Information Office of Opus Dei** ** ******

 ****In compliance with the principle of transparency adopted by the International Standards for the Protection of Privacy Act on November 5, 2009, and with the rules on data protection, we inform you that personal information collected on this site may be incorporated into and processed in the files of the owner Entity for its own purposes and for the management of its activities, as well as for other purposes, including fulfilling your requests for information, comments and inquiries, newsletter sign-up, contacting you in the way you request, by telephone or email—through your email address—and/or to ensure proper attention to our communications with you.

Users are notified that, and expressly consent to, the titular Entity, as the file manager, processing and ceding for legitimate purposes, personal data, including photographs of the user, solely to the entities participating in its activities, development and organizational purposes and to the persons and entities directly associated with this Entity.

In keeping with our commitment to respect for privacy, this Entity has set as a high priority to carefully maintain as confidential all information you may have entrusted us with, and it also has the technical, organizational and human resources necessary to ensure that only authorized personnel have access to your data, with full respect for your privacy.

Please note that at any time you may exercise your right of access, correction, deletion and opposition to the use of your personal data in our files, by letter accompanied by a copy of an official ID document, addressed to info@opusdei.org.

 _Last modified: March 2014_

## Privacy policy and cookies

No personal information is collected through this site, or is transferred to third parties without your prior knowledge and consent. Data is collected, used, or transferred to third parties solely to provide the best services through this website and in order to improve its usability and navigation. By browsing on the website, you give your consent for us to analyze the number of pages visited, the number of visits and the activity of visitors to the website and their frequency of use. For this purpose, the statistical data compiled by the relevant Internet Service Provider are used.

The present Cookies Policy is intended to inform you clearly and precisely about the cookies used in this website. Should you need more information about the cookies used on this website, you can send an email to the following address:

Additional information:

 **What are cookies?**

A cookie is a small piece of text that the websites you visit send to the browser, and allows the website to remember information about your visit, preferred language and other options, which can facilitate your next visit and help you find the site more useful. Cookies play a very important role and contribute to a better user experience.

 **Why are they important?**

Cookies allow us to make this website better, faster and safer. For example, cookies help us to:

\- Enable certain features.

\- Provide a highly personalized experience.

\- Ensure security.

 **What types of Cookies does this site use?**

 **Statistical analysis cookies:**

These cookies allow us to quantify the number of visitors and statistically analyze how users use our facilities, helping us improve navigation on the website and its functionality.

 **Cookies of a technical or personalization character:**

These cookies are associated with the user's session, so that we can improve the experience of navigation within the website. In particular, they allow us to save your preference concerning the top banner of the front page of the website. These cookies record in your computer whether you want to see the banner or main image on the cover of this web every time you visit.

 **How I can set my cookies? How I can remove them?**

You can allow, block or delete cookies installed on your computer by configuring the options for your specific Internet browser:

\- [Internet Explorer](http://windows.microsoft.com/es-es/windows-vista/block-or-allow-cookies)

\- [Mozilla Firefox](https://support.mozilla.org/es/kb/habilitar-y-deshabilitar-cookies-que-los-sitios-we)

\- [Google Chrome](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=es)

\- [Chrome para Android](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/2392971?hl=es)

\- [Safari](https://support.apple.com/kb/ph5042)

\- [Safari para IOS](https://support.apple.com/kb/ht1677?viewlocale=es_es&locale=es_es) (iPhone y iPad)

You can still use the website if you chose to reject the installation of cookies, but the use of some services may be limited and therefore your experience on our website may be less satisfactory.

If at any given time you wish to withdraw your consent to this Cookie Policy, you need to delete the cookies stored by means of adjustments and settings in your Internet browser.

 **Who uses cookies from this site?**

In our organization we work with other companies that help us obtain statistics of visitors, pages viewed and other indicators of the activity of our site.

 **In our organization we never keep the personal data of our users, except for the IP** address, according to what is stated in this Notice.

 **Consent**

By navigating and staying on this website you are consenting to the use made of the aforementioned cookies, under the conditions contained in this Cookies Policy.

You can learn more about us via our legal notice or by mail to this address [info@vitruvio.org](mailto:info@vitruvio.org).
